Lesson 49. The ideal servant. It is a good thing my aunt Harriet died years ago. If she were
第49课。理想的仆人。我的哈丽雅特姨妈几年前去世是一件好事。如果她是
alive today she would not be able to air her views on her favorite topic of conversation.
今天活着，她将无法对自己最喜欢的谈话话题发表自己的看法。
Domestic servants. Aunt Harriet lived in that leisurely age when servants were employed to do
家庭仆人。哈里特姨妈住在那个悠闲的年龄，当时雇用了仆人
rambling: adj. 杂乱无章的, sentimentally: adv. 感情上，多情地
housework. She had a huge, rambling country house called, the Gables. She was sentimentally attached
家务。她有一个巨大的杂乱无章的乡间别墅，叫山墙。她情绪依恋
to this house. For even though it was far too big for her needs, she persisted in living there
到这所房子。因为即使她的需求太大了，她仍然坚持住在那里
lavishly: adv. 慷慨地，大方地
long after her husband's death. Before she grew old, Aunt Harriet used to entertain lavishly.
丈夫去世很久。在她变老之前，哈丽雅特姨妈曾经很娱乐。
I often visited the Gables when I was boy. No matter how many guests were present, the
我小时候经常去山墙。不管有多少客人，
great house was always a maculad. The parkay floors shown like mirrors. Highly polished silver was
伟大的房子一直是玛利亚德。像镜子一样显示的Parkay地板。高度抛光的银是
gleam: v.   发亮，闪光
displayed in gleaming glass cabinets. Even my uncle's huge collection of books was kept miraculously
显示在闪闪发光的玻璃柜中。甚至我叔叔的大量书籍都被奇迹般地保存下来
preside: v.   指挥, invisible: adj. 看不见的，无形的, scrub: v.   擦拭，刷洗
free from dust-dant Harriet presided over an invisible army of servants that continuously scrubbed,
没有尘土飞扬的哈丽雅特主持一支隐形的仆人军队，这些仆人不断擦洗，
cleaned, and polished. She always referred to them as the shifting population. For they came
清洁和抛光。她总是将他们称为变化的人口。因为他们来了
and went with such frequency that I never even got a chance to learn their names. Though my aunt
并以这样的频率走了，我什至从未有机会学习他们的名字。虽然我的姨妈
enlightened: adj. 开明的
pursued what was. In those days, an enlightened policy, in that she never allowed her domestic staff
追求什么。在那些日子里，一项开明的政策，因为她从未允许她的国内员工
to work more than eight hours a day. She was extremely difficult to please. While she always
每天工作八个小时以上。她很难取悦。而她总是
fickleness: n.   变化无常, unrelenting: adj. 不屈不挠的，不松懈的确良
criticized the fickleness of human nature, she carried on an unrelenting search for the ideal
批评人性的善变，她不屈不挠地寻找理想
disillusion: v.   使幻想破灭的
servant to the end of her days. Even after she had been sadly disillusioned by Bessie, Bessie worked
仆人到她的日子结束。即使在她被贝西（Bessie）幻灭后，贝西（Bessie）也工作了
for Aunt Harriet for three years. During that time she so gained my aunt's confidence that she was
为哈丽雅特姨妈三年。在那段时间里，她使我的姨妈充满信心
put in charge of the domestic staff. Aunt Harriet could not find words to praise Bessie's
负责国内员工。哈丽雅特姨妈找不到赞美贝西的话
qualification: n.    资格，能力
industriousness and efficiency. In addition to all her other qualifications, Bessie was an expert cook.
勤奋和效率。除了所有其他资格外，贝西还是一位专业的厨师。
She acted the role of the perfect servant for three years before Aunt Harriet discovered her.
在哈丽雅特姨妈发现她之前，她扮演了完美仆人的角色三年。
Little weakness. After being absent from the gables for a week, my aunt unexpectedly returned
小弱点。在山墙缺席一个星期之后，我的姨妈意外回来了
one afternoon with a party of guests and instructed Bessie to prepare. Dinner. No only was the meal well
一个下午与客人聚会，并指示贝西做准备。晚餐。这顿饭不仅很好
below the usual standard, but Bessie seemed unable to walk steadily. She bumped into the furniture
低于通常的标准，但贝西似乎无法稳定行走。她撞到家具
and kept mumbling about the guests. When she came in with the last course, a huge pudding,
并一直在喃喃自语。当她参加上一门课程，一个巨大的布丁时，
she tripped on the carpet and the pudding went flying through the air. Narely missed my aunt
她绊倒在地毯上，布丁飞过空中。毫无疑问我的姑姑
mirth: n.   欢笑，高兴
and crashed on the dining table with considerable force. Though this caused great mirth among the guests.
并用相当大的力量在餐桌上坠毁。尽管这在客人中引起了极大的欢乐。
Aunt Harriet was horrified. She reluctantly came to the conclusion that Bessie was drunk.
哈丽雅特姨妈很害怕。她勉强得出结论是贝西喝醉了。
The guests had, of course, realized this from the moment Bessie opened the door for them and
当然，客人从贝西（Bessie）为他们打开大门的那一刻就意识到了这一点
long before the final catastrophe had had a difficult time trying to conceal their amusement.
在最后一场灾难很难掩盖自己的娱乐之前很久。
The poor girl was dismissed instantly. After her departure, Aunt Harriet discovered that there
这个可怜的女孩立即被解雇。她离开后，哈丽雅特姨妈发现那里
were piles of empty wine bottles of all shapes and sizes neatly. Stacked in what had once been
是一堆整齐的所有形状和尺寸的空葡萄酒瓶。堆放在曾经的事物中
Bessie's wardrobe, they had mysteriously found their way there from the wine cellar.
贝西的衣柜，他们神秘地从酒窖里找到了自己的路。